Tonight breaking news indicted.
Another critic of President Trump indicted.
The third indictment in three weeks.
This time Trump's one time national security adviser
John Bolton accused of mishandling classified documents.
It comes after former FBI director James
Comey also critical of Trump indicted.
At New York Attorney General Letitia James indicted too.
We'll go live to Pierre Thomas.
Also breaking tonight the awful images coming in right now.
There is an extraordinary rescue effort underway.
The devastating
storm that hit Alaska.
Entire towns have been wiped away.
Hundreds now being airlifted including families and children.
Matt Guptman on these rescues underway.
Tonight after the newest strike on a boat off Venezuela there is news
three American B 52 bombers are now flying near the Venezuelan coast.
President Trump also authorizing
covert CIA missions inside Venezuela.
Martha Raddatz standing by with late
reporting what's behind all of this.
Tonight President Trump revealing he spoke with Vladimir
Putin today for more than two hours saying they will
have another major meeting after their Alaska summit.
This time in Hungary the president saying he asked
Putin today how would you like it if I gave U.S.
Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine to use against Russia.
Tonight the dramatic images of tear gas and violent
clashes with federal agents in Chicago and this evening a
judge now ordering those agents to wear body cameras.
That judge saying she was startled by the
images of the clashes in Philadelphia.
Tonight the desperate search for a missing health care
worker last seen leaving for work nearly two weeks ago.
And what we've learned tonight a passenger jet forced
to make an emergency landing authority say a 61
year old woman began assaulting crew members tonight.
There is breaking news as we come on.
We have learned Kisco founder Ace Freely has
died and this evening Diane Keaton's cause of
death now revealed what her family is now saying.
And tonight here the new and deeply moving tribute from actor
Al Pacino what he's now saying about Diane Keaton on screen off
screen and what he reveals in this raw and heartfelt goodbye.
From ABC News World headquarters in New York.
This is world news tonight with David Bjor.
Good evening.
We begin tonight here with the breaking
news for the third time in three weeks.
Another one of President Trump's most outspoken
critics now indicted by a federal grand jury.
This time Trump's former national security adviser
John Bolton the Justice Department tonight
accusing Bolton of mishandling classified documents.
Bolton who played a major role in the first Trump
administration once writing after witnessing the
president up close that he was quote not fit for office.
Tonight Bolton is indicted.
The FBI searching his home in Maryland in August Bolton denying he
illegally removed classified materials.
The president publicly attacking Bolton since
he left the first administration revoking his
security clearance and secret service protection.
Tonight's newest indictment comes after former FBI director
James Comey was indicted and just days ago New York
Attorney General Letitia James indicted to ABC's chief
justice correspondent Pierre Thomas leading us off tonight.
Tonight for the third time in three weeks the
Justice Department pursuing criminal charges against
one of President Trump's political enemies.
First it was former FBI director James Comey then
New York State Attorney General Letitia James.
Now the president's former national security
adviser turned outspoken critic John Bolton.
Tonight Bolton indicted by a federal grand jury on 18 felony counts
for alleged illegal transmission and retention of classified documents.
I think he's you know a bad person.
I think he's a bad guy.
Yeah he's a bad guy.
Too bad but it's the way it goes.
That's the way it goes right.
The president has been railing against Bolton for years
ever since he published a tell-all book about his
time in the administration the room where it happened.
He took classified information
then he published it during the presidency.
It's not you know it's one thing to write a book after during
and I believe that he's a criminal and I
believe frankly he should go to jail for that.
In August federal agents searched Bolton's home in Maryland.
What?
What were they looking for?
An office in Washington.
The president insisted he knew nothing about it.
I purposely don't want to really get involved in it.
I'm not a fan of John Bolton.
I thought it was a sleazebag actually.
Bolton was indicted for allegedly emailing more than a thousand pages
of information about his activities as national security advisors
with two members of his family in the form of diary like entries.
Prosecutors say after Bolton left office a cyber
actor believed to be associated with Iran hacked
his personal email and obtained that information.
Prosecutors also say documents found in Bolton's home range
from sensitive to top secret and include details about a
future attack by an adversarial group in another country
and details about a foreign adversaries missile launch plans
as well as plans of a covert action by the US government.
But Bolton's attorney said the documents were no longer considered
classified and Bolton himself has long denied any wrongdoing.
Do you fear at all you could be prosecuted?
Look under Donald Trump no regular rules here apply but I
am confident that there's no national security information,
no classified information in the book.
I didn't intend to write anything
that revealed classified information.
David this investigation began in the Biden administration.
Tonight Bolton's attorney Abby
Lowell releasing a statement that Bolton did
not retain or share classified information.
But he quote kept diaries emphasizing that this is not a crime.
But David if convicted
of all these charges he faces potentially decades in prison.
David.
Pierre Thomas leading us off here tonight.
Pierre thank you.
Now to the other breaking
story unfolding the awful images coming in.
There's an extraordinary rescue effort tonight
now underway in Alaska.
Families and children being lifted to safety.
Hundreds of people
now being airlifted packed onto military
planes there following a devastating storm.
Entire
towns wiped away.
Matt Guppman with the images coming in tonight.
Tonight after powerful storms
packing 100 mile per hour winds swept parts of
entire towns into the Bering Sea. That massive
military effort in Alaska to get hundreds out of harm's way.
This Boeing C-17 crammed
with 300 evacuees touching down at Joint Base
Elmendorf Richardson in Anchorage overnight.
Families some with small children some in wheelchairs pouring out.
The National Guard
calling it one of the biggest airlift operations in Alaska history.
The storms fueled by remnants of a typhoon that tore across
the Pacific barreling into Western Alaska over the weekend.
That devastating storm surge flooding
the towns of Kipnook and Quigillingawk.
Tribal Administrator Tristan Carl
watched his uncle's home being swept away.
I saw my cousin and my nephew in there and I never
heard panicking or yelling like that ever before.
This is the damage left behind in Kipnook the surging
sea turning already melting permafrost into muck.
And the only way out by air.
Coast Guard helicopters hoisting dozens
of residents out of the flood waters.
The woman who shot this video says her home is now gone.
And David this monster storm has already left one
person dead two people missing in just a short time ago.
I spoke with emergency management officials in Alaska
who say that this is still a very dynamic situation
and that right now tonight they are still evacuating
a couple of hundred people from those outlying areas.
David.
Yeah those are just extraordinary images coming in Matt.
Thank you.
Tonight after the newest strike on a boat off Venezuela
we've now learned this evening there are three American
B-52 bombers now flying near the Venezuelan coast.
And President Trump tonight authorizing
covert CIA missions inside Venezuela now.
So Martha Raditz with late reporting tonight what's behind this.
Tonight the U.S.
military launching a new attack on a boat off of Venezuela.
A U.S.
official telling ABC this time there were survivors.
This as we're learning of a massive show
of military force off Venezuela's coast.
ABC confirming three nuclear capable B-52 heavy bombers
flew for hours in the Caribbean waters
less than 90 miles from Venezuela.
The move comes in the midst of a major U.S.
military buildup in the region of some 10,000 U.S.
troops including special operations helicopters the kind used by
Navy SEALs and Delta Force now conducting exercises in the Caribbean.
This most recent boat strike is at least the sixth on what the
administration claims are vessels operated by drug cartels.
With President Trump now authorizing CIA missions
in Venezuela and threatening ground strikes as well.
We have a lot of drugs coming in from Venezuela and a
lot of the Venezuelan drugs come in through the sea.
So you get to see that.
But we're going to stop them by land also.
Trump blames Venezuela's president Nicholas
Maduro for drugs coming into the U.S.
and is trying to pressure him to step down.
The administration offering 50 million dollars for information
leading to his arrest and conviction on drug charges.
And tonight David we're learning that Admiral Alvin Holsey
who is overseeing these operations is stepping down.
He has been on the job for less than a year.
He is one of numerous senior officers who have resigned or been kicked
out by Secretary Pete Hegseth since President Trump took office.
David.
Martha Raditz on this tonight for us.
Martha thank you.
Late today President Trump revealing he spoke with
Vladimir Putin for more than two hours today saying
after the Alaska summit they will now meet again.
And the president says he asked Putin
directly how would you like it if I gave U.S.
Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine?
Here's Mary Bruce.
Just two months after his Alaska summit
with Vladimir Putin failed to yield results,
and
with Russia intensifying its bombing of
Ukraine and flying drones over NATO countries,
President
Trump tonight says he plans to meet
with Putin again in the coming weeks,
this time in Hungary.
I think Alaska actually set a stage,
and that wasn't very long ago,
but it set a stage.
Trump today speaking on the phone with Putin for more than two hours.
Tomorrow he'll meet with Ukrainian
President Zelensky at the White House.
Zelensky has been asking Trump for powerful
Tomahawk missiles capable of striking deep
inside of Russia,
something Trump said he discussed with Putin today.
I did actually say,
would you mind if I gave a couple of
thousand Tomahawks to your opposition?
I did say that to him.
I said it just that way.
He didn't like the idea.
And Zelensky today arriving in Washington
for that Oval Office meeting tomorrow.
As for
Trump's sit down with Putin,
the president says his top advisors will meet with their
Russian counterparts next week.
He says his face-to-face with Putin will come shortly
after.
David.
Mary Roussel, live at the White House tonight.
Mary, thank you.
Tonight,
a federal judge responding to those
dramatic images coming out of Chicago,
the
tear gas and violent clashes with federal
agents sent in by the Trump administration.
That judge now ordering agents to turn their body cameras on.
The judge saying she was startled by the images of the clashes.
Alex Prez tonight from Chicago.
After seeing these images of violent clashes in
Chicago ending with tear gas used on protesters,
tonight,
a judge says federal agents who have body cameras must wear them
during the Trump administration's sweeping immigration crackdown.
U.S.
District Judge Sarah Ellis saying she is deeply
concerned with apparent violations of her earlier order
restricting the use of force and riot control weapons.
After video showed ICE agents striking a
minister in the head with pepper balls.
If you've got a bunch of peaceful protesters,
then you can't shoot them in the head.
You can't deploy tear gas.
You can't use flash bang grenades.
You can't drive a car through a crowd.
The judge pointing to this border patrol chase through
a neighborhood that ended with this pit maneuver.
Chicago residents and protesters are now documenting more encounters.
He's a citizen!
You don't know what's going on,
so get the f*** back!
Illinois's governor,
who hasn't asked for federal help today,
praised the judge's order.
The federal agents are required to have body cameras on them because
they clearly lie about what goes on.
And David,
the judge also ordered the field director of ICE here in Chicago
to appear before the court and answer questions on Monday.
David?
Alex Prez from Chicago tonight.
Thank you.
Now to the desperate search for a missing
health care worker in Philadelphia tonight.
She was last seen leaving for work nearly two weeks ago now.
Here's Morgan Norwood.
Tonight,
the urgent search for a missing Philadelphia woman.
Authorities are reigning 21-year-old
Keon King on charges of kidnapping
and the disappearance of Kata Scott,
the health care
worker now missing for 12 days,
her family desperate for answers.
I'm hopeful we are going to find Kata.
We raised a strong,
confident, intelligent young
woman,
so I'm going to remain confident that she's okay.
Miss Kata vanished after her overnight shift
at this assistant living facility on October
4th. Her car found abandoned in the parking lot.
Authorities say the suspect was the last
person in contact with the 23-year-old.
We do not know where Miss Scott is.
Mr. King
is the last person we believe to be in contact
with her and that he was in contact with her
when she went offline,
meaning her phone,
everything.
New tips leading detectives to
this abandoned elementary school.
Police deploying drones and canines saying they located Scott's
debit card and a phone case.
Also saying they found a vehicle of
interest near the suspect's apartment.
Authorities say before Kata went missing,
she told family she was being harassed.
It's unclear if by King.
And David,
police say that suspect was already on their
radar from a different alleged kidnapping
case earlier this year.
He's now being held on a two and a half
million dollar bail due back in court
next month.
David?
Morgan Norwood with us tonight.
Morgan, thank you.
When we come back here the fall
today,
former Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell falling
while answering a question on the ice crackdowns.
The 83 year old losing his footing in the Capitol.
We do have news on his condition coming in.
We have also just learned tonight that Ace Freely,
a founding member of the legendary rock group Kiss,
has now died.
What his family just revealed here.
And Diane Keaton's family tonight now revealing her cause of death.
And also right here,
the new and deeply moving tribute tonight from actor
Al Pacino about Keaton on screen and off screen.
What he now reveals in his raw and horror
felt goodbye tonight.
Tonight,
Kiss founding member and lead guitarist Ace Freely has died.
His family says he passed away peacefully
surrounded by family after a recent fall at home.
Freely helped to form the iconic rock band Kiss back in the early
70s. He was a Grammy nominee and a rock and roll Hall of Famer.
Ace Freely was just 74
Kentucky Senator Mitch McConnell falling at the Capitol today.
The 83 year old falling while being asked
a question about the ice crackdowns.
He got up and continued walking with the help of staff.
A
folio survivor McConnell has had similar incidents in the past.
Earlier this year,
he said he would not be seeking reelection.
When we come back here tonight,
the passenger plane,
the emergency landing,
they say a 61 year old woman began attacking crew.
What we've learned.
We've also learned tonight Diane
Keaton's cause of death.
Tonight to the index of other news,
Alaska Airlines has a flight from Portland to Dallas
was forced to make an emergency landing in Boise,
Idaho because of an unruly passenger.
Police saying the 61 year old female
passenger struck two airline employees
on that flight on Tuesday.
Is this suspect being detained by passengers?
Do we know the status of the situation there?
There's folks in Lexicox right now.
The passenger was arrested and is now facing two counts of battery.
Tonight in 15 states across the northern
part of the country from New York to Idaho,
Montana,
all the way up to Alaska could get quite a show tonight.
The northern lights could be visible.
Expected to peak this evening right into the overnight hours.
Send us your images
when we come back here tonight.
Diane Keaton's cause of death revealed
what her family is now saying tonight.
An actor Al Pacino
and his new and deeply personal tribute to Diane Keaton tonight.
Finally,
tonight here,
Diane Keaton's family now revealing her cause of death
and actor Al Pacino tonight with a new and heartfelt tribute tonight.
So many fans and colleagues,
fellow actors saying Diane Keaton's death
hit them in unexpected ways that she
was a light on screen and off tonight.
Her family now telling People magazine they're quote
grateful for the extraordinary messages of love and support
and that their beloved Diane passed away from pneumonia.
Her final Instagram post was Keaton with her beloved dog Reggie.
She gave away millions to causes over the years.
The Helen Woodward Animal Center in Santa Fe,
California,
telling us tonight it's impossible to count the
number of lives that Diane has saved tonight.
They're seeing donations in memory of Diane.
Keaton famously never married and she never minded talking about it.
You don't want to get married.
Oh, I'd like to get married, yeah.
You got that wrong.
I didn't know that you wanted to get married.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, very bad.
And what happened was nobody ever asked me.
Oh.
Well, somebody will now.
No, I don't think so.
Not after this show.
Michael, why did you come here?
And tonight here,
the new tribute from Al Pacino,
his raw and heartfelt words.
They start alongside one another in the Godfather movies.
Please stop it, Michael.
It's too late.
The two were together on screen and off for years.
Tonight,
Al Pacino telling Deadline,
when I first heard the news,
I was shaken.
Diane was my partner,
my friend,
someone who brought me happiness and on more than
one occasion influenced the direction of my life.
On screen,
she was magnetic,
lightning and charm,
hurricanes and tenderness.
She was a wonder.
And he finished by saying,
I will always remember her.
She could fly.
And in my heart, she always will.
Al Pacino was among the actors who honored Diane Keaton for
the American Film Institute's Lifetime Achievement Award.
We all met for the first time, Diane.
I don't know if you remember it.
Pacino saying the first time they met was a
restaurant in Harlem with the cast of The Godfather.
There was Marlon Brando.
He was there,
the Godfather,
at the head of the table.
And I remember he got up
early on and introduced himself and walked over to Diane.
And he said,
hi, Diane,
I'm Marlon Brando.
And she looked up, shook his hand and said,
yeah, right.
OK, good.
That's fine.
OK, you're right.
And then Pacino addressing Diane Keaton directly.
You're an artist, Diane.
You're a great artist.
I remember it and I love it.
And I love
you forever.
Thank you.
Al Pacino on Diane Keaton.
I'm David Muir.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Good night.
has won the Emmy for Best Live News
Program for the third year in a row.